<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>playgrounds 4 on Swift on iPad</title>
    <link>https://swiftonipad.com/tags/playgrounds-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in playgrounds 4 on Swift on iPad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Swift on iPad. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 12:50:26 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swiftonipad.com/tags/playgrounds-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple releases sample apps tutorials for Swift Playgrounds and Xcode</title>
      <link>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/official-sample-apps-tutorials-for-playgrounds-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 12:50:26 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/official-sample-apps-tutorials-for-playgrounds-released/</guid>
      <description>Apple has dropped ten (10) sample apps tutorials for newly released Playgrounds 4 and Xcode. &amp;lsquo;Sample Apps Tutorials&amp;rsquo; page lists 4 chapters containing multiple apps to showcase different techniques to users like navigating between pages, fetching content from servers, handling user input and more.
On every sample app&amp;rsquo;s page, you will find project&amp;rsquo;s summary, a button to download project files, and step by step explanation of code. To follow the tutorials you will need Swift Playgrounds 4 or later on your iPad, and Xcode 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Playgrounds 4 released for iPad and Mac</title>
      <link>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/swift-playgrounds-4-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 23:27:52 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/swift-playgrounds-4-released/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the wait is finally over now. Apple just dropped the long awaited update for Swift Playgrounds, you can download the latest version from App Store (download links at bottom). It brings the ability to develop iPhone and iPad apps right from any iPad running iPadOS 15.2 or later. So if your iPad got the iPadOS 15 update, you are in for the treat.
However for the Mac app, story is different, it just adds support for Swift 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Playgrounds 4 release imminent</title>
      <link>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/swift-playgrounds-4-release-imminent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 07:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/swift-playgrounds-4-release-imminent/</guid>
      <description>Finally seems like the wait is about to get over and soon you will be able to install Swift Playgrounds 4 on your iPads. Apple.com still mentions vague &amp;ldquo;available late 2021&amp;rdquo; release date, but you should expect the release within a couple of weeks. Why? Here are some points to back it:
Update: Apple released final versions of Xocde 13.2 and iPadOS 15.2 on December 13th, but we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any prominent progress regarding Swift Playgrounds 4 yet, except that &amp;ldquo;Available late 2021&amp;rdquo; footnote has been removed from iPadOS 15 page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Playgrounds 4: Things we know so far</title>
      <link>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/swift-playgrounds-4-what-we-know-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:19:34 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftonipad.com/posts/swift-playgrounds-4-what-we-know-so-far/</guid>
      <description>During WWDC 2021 keynote Craig Fedrighi teased Playgrounds 4 for iPad by saying that it will bring the ability to “build apps on iPad”. Later that day we saw a short demo of the new Playgrounds during “Platforms State of the Union”, a developer centric keynote that dives deeper into the newly announced tools and technologies. Since that day we haven&amp;rsquo;t heard anything more about the Playgrounds 4 update.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
